VINOD KUMAR

DATA ANALYST

CONTACT

- +91-9929233229
- ¥ 94vk.saini@gmail.com
- Vill. Manshirpur, Alwar

#Linkedin.com/in/vinod-kumara0019a248

SKILLS

POWER BI DEVELOPER

ADVANCE EXCEL DEVELOPER

DAX FUNCTIONS

EXCEL FORMULAS AND FUNCTIONS

EDUCATION

DEGREE/MECH. ENGINEERING

Sunrise University Alwar

2014 - 2017

DIPLOMA MECH. ENGINEERING

Sunrise University Alwar

2011- 2014

BI-PROJECTS

·Energy Consumption Project

·Retail Sales Project

·Housing Market Project

PROFILE

Skilled data analyst with more than 1 year 3 Months of industry experience in collecting, organizing, interpreting and disseminating various types of statistical figures. Energetic presenter and confident communicator with the abilityto circulate information in a way that is clear, efficient and beneficial for end users. Creative in finding solutions to problems and determining modifications for optimal use of organizational data.

EXPERIENCE

POWER BI DEVELOPER

Ashok Leyland | Alwar | May 2022 - Aug 2023

Power BI Developers roles and responsibility includes transforming raw data to valuable and meaningful insights in the form of appealing dashboards and reports.

- Study, analyze and understand business requirements in context to business intelligence.
- Design and map data models to shift raw data into meaningful insights.
- Utilize Power BI to build interactive and visually appealing dashboards and reports.
- Analyze pervious and present data for better decision making
- Develop strong data documentation about algorithms, parameters, models
- Perform detailed analysis on tested and deployed Power BI scripts
- Run DAX queries and functions in Power BI

TESTING ENGINEER

Tafe Motors | Alwar | Mar 2019 - Apr 2022

The role of Test Engineer is to thoroughly check materials, procedures and mechanical or electrical systems to ensure that customers get high-quality, functional products. They run tests on various components and features in order to identify and fix technical issues.

- ·My job was to test the Engine on the test bed.
- I used to do Oil Consumption, Fuel Consumption, Emissions Test, and Engine Components test as per company standards.
- If the final result was positive, I would have taken permission from my manager to stop the project.

INTERNSHIP TRAINING

Rajesh Motors | Alwar | Oct 2018 - Feb 2019